VADIM DOLMATOV



Personal

Address
108801 Moscow

Phone number +79031550306

Email dolmat.vadim@gmail.com

Date of birth
16-11-1988

Gender Male

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/vdolmatov

Skills

PLC	••••
SCADA	••••
Siemens	••••
Schneider	••••
Yokogawa	••••
SQL	• • • • •
C#	• • • • •
Network	• • • • •
Commissioning	••••
Instrumentation	••••
Design	

Languages

Russian	••••
English	••••
Chinese	••••
Ukrainian	••••

Automation engineer with 6+ years of experience in the development of automated control systems in the field of production, processing, transportation and storage of oil, oil products and gas. There is significant engineering experience, participation in all stages of the development of an automated process control systems from design to commissioning at enterprises in Russia, Turkmenistan and Kazakhstan.

Proficient with modern instrumentation, control cabinet equipment, PLC. Completed several projects using Siemens, Schneider, Yokogawa systems. Knowledge of communication protocols (Modbus, Profibus, ProfiNet, TCP/IP).

Skills in object-oriented programming (C#), databases (MS SQL, MySQL), network

Work experience

equipment.

Instrumentation and Control Engineer

Nov 2018 - Present

Automation and Service LLP, Moscow

- 1. Development of software for PLC, SCADA, HMI panels.
- 2. Supervising, quality control.
- 3. Commissioning.
- 4. Development of technical documentation.

Instrumentation and Control Engineer

Mar 2016 - Nov 2018

PRIZ JSC, Moscow

- 1. Development of software for PLC, SCADA, HMI panels.
- 2. Supervising, quality control.
- 3. Commissioning.
- 4. Development of technical documentation.

Instrumentation and Control Engineer

Aug 2014 - Dec 2015

NEKO LLP, Maloyaroslavets, Kaluga region

- 1. Design automated and safety systems for heating (boilers, IHP, CHP) and gas generator sets.
- 2. PLC programming.
- 3. Supervising, quality control.
- 4. Commissioning.

Education and Qualifications

Master's degree 2005 - 2010

Kharkiv National University of Radioelectronics, Kharkiv

Flexible computer systems and robotics

Master's degree 2008 - 2011

Kharkiv National University of Radioelectronics, Kharkiv

Automation in Banking

Courses

Modicon BME M580 controller configuration features

Schneider Electric

Unity Pro Application Development Environment - Advanced

Schneider Electric

Ethernet-based industrial communications for Modicon Schneider Electric

Nov 2017

Sep 2017

Oct 2017

20483B. Programming on C #

Nov 2017

Autonomous Non-Profit Organization of Additional VocationalEducation "IT Academy"

Participation in projects

Automation and Service LLP

1. 2018 - 2019. Kharampurskoe gas field (Yamalo-Nenets Autonomous region)

Development of DCS and ESD systems for field facilities.

Personal participation:

- software development for Yokogawa Stardom and FAST/Tools systems;
- Factory acceptance test (FAT).

PLC - Stardom FCN500, SCADA - FAST/Tools, HMI - Weintek

2. 2019. Zhaikmunai LLP - Chinarevskoye gas field (Kazakhstan)

Addition to the OTU a new equipment: vertical steel tanks, pumping units, valves, instrumentation.

Personal participation:

- configuring the PLC with new distributed units without stopping production;
- · PLC program correction;
- adding new technological positions to the SCADA project;
- · commissioning.

PLC - Siemens S7-400H, distributed system - ET200M, SCADA - WinCC.

3. 2019. Vostochno-Messoyakhskoye field (Yamalo-Nenets Autonomous region)

Personal participation: software development for local system integration.

PLC - Stardom FCN500, SCADA - FAST/Tools

4. 2019. ZapSibNeftekhim (Tobolsk)

Commissioning

Personal participation:

- PLC program correction;
- HMI correction;
- technical support.

DCS - Yokogawa Centum, local PLC - Yokogawa FA-M3, HMI - STAHL.

5. 2020. Amursky GPP (Amur region)

Commissioning supervision.

DCS - Yokogawa Centum, ESD - Yokogawa ProSafe.

6. 2020. Vostochno-Messoyakhskoye field (Yamalo-Nenets Autonomous region)

Personal participation: software development for local system integration, commissioning.

PLC - Stardom FCN500, SCADA - FAST/Tools, ESD - ProSafe.

PRIZ JSC

1. 2016. LUKOIL - Complex oil terminal (Kaliningrad region)

Addition to the complex a new equipment: vertical steel tanks, filtration units.

Personal participation - design.

2. 2016. LUKOIL - Fuel filling complex in Koltsovo Airport (Yekaterinburg)

Comissioning

Personal participation:

- software development for PLC and SCADA;
- comissioning of instrumentation, cabinet equipment, valves and frequency converters.

For the DCS was used Siemens S7-400H with ET-200M distributed peripherals, for the ESD - IM-151-8F-CPU.

3. 2017. Gazprom neftekhim Salavat (Republic of Bashkortostan)

Design of rail tanker loading unit.

4. 2017. Turkmenbashi Refinery (Turkmenistan)

Commissioning of steam superheat unit.

PLC Siemens S7-300 F-CPU, SCADA WinCC.

5. 2018. LUKOIL - Fuel filling complex in Sheremetyevo Airport (Moscow)

Design DCS and ESD, QA/QC, Commissioning.

Personal participation:

- · Design;
- Management of commissioning team;
- Integration of local systems;
- PLC programming.

For the DCS was used PLC Schneider Modicon M580 and M340, SCADA - Schneider Citect, distributed peripherals - Simatic ET200IS via Profibus.